本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
圣  城  风  云
『第一季  第七集』
翻译  Jasmine雪
翻译  LyraL
翻译  ala365
翻译  苏小黛
翻译  小易
时间轴  veryink
校对  苏小黛
后期  渔夫
特效  WiLL
总监制  苏小黛
把这些拿楼下去  再去帮帮西比尔
Take those downstairs and then go and assist Sybil.
遵命  小姐
Yes, my lady.
对这"春光"还满意吗
Do you enjoy the view?
小姐
Lady.
求您了  我求您
Please, I beg you.
你那脏手在玷污我的裙子之前
What were you doing with that hand
还做了些什么
before you used it to sully my dress?
敬爱的小姐  我爱您
My lady, I love you.
是吗
Do you?
你就这样证明你对我的爱意的吗
This is how you prove it?
我愿为您做任何事
I'll do anything.
任何事
Anything.
跟我来
Come with me.
告诉她你的名字
Tell her your name.
豪威尔
Harwel.
你能为我做些什么呢  豪威尔
And what have you offered me, Harwel?
您让我做什么我就做什么
Whatever you wish of me.
让他准备好
Get him prepared.
其他的都准备好了吗
Is everything else ready?
是的
Yes.
你确定亚瑟会来吗
You're sure that Arthur will come?
这个私生子内心迫切的想要一个家
His bastard's heart craves a family.
我不是家人又是何人呢
And what am I, if not family?
还有更好的方法可以进入他的内心世界吗
What better way to get inside his head?
把肉弄得更咸些  拿出最烈的酒
Double salt the meat and bring out the strongest ale.
遵命  小姐
Yes, my lady.
我要他们觉得口渴  我要灌醉他们
I want them thirsty and drunk.
我们要向亚瑟证明
We'll prove to Arthur just how loyal
我们无尚的忠心
and devoted we are.
摩根曾和杀害我们双亲的人结盟
Morgan was allied with the man who killed both our parents.
现在却成了我们的挚友吗
But now we're the best of friends?
她提醒过我们  他会来袭
She warned us of his attack.
若不是她  我们可能早丧命了
Without her, we could have all died.
我要提醒你  她城堡的宴会是鸿门宴啊
I'm warning you. A feast at her castle is a risk.
作为你弟弟  我告诉你要摒弃前嫌
And as your brother, I'm telling you, some wounds have to heal.
况且  我已和她共进过晚餐
Besides, I've already broken
现在仍完好无损地活着
bread with her and lived to tell the tale.
你怎么看
What do you think?
我觉得这主意不错  我很期待
I think it's a marvellous idea. I'm looking forward to it.
梅林都不担心  我还担心个什么劲
If Merlin's not worried, I'm not worried.
如果不赴约  我就搞不明白摩根的阴谋
If we don't go, I can't work out what Morgan's up to.
而且我很想念故土
Besides, I miss the old place,
享用顿美食对我们有益无害
and a feast will do us all good.
卡米洛特或许已有了藏书馆和军械库
Camelot might have a library and an armoury,
但我们还没有可坐下吃饭的餐桌
but we haven't got a table to sit at.
我们就这样毫不设防的离开吗
So we leave it undefended?
我们招募到人了
We've recruited.
高文训练过他们了  我们不缺精兵良将
Gawain's trained them. We don't lack good soldiers.
我们只缺酒
Just ale.
彭德拉根堡佳酿颇多
And Castle Pendragon has plenty of that.
喝醉前我们先好好舒展下筋骨吧
Let's get a move on before it's all been drunk!
-欢迎  我的国王  -我是你弟弟
- Welcome, my king. - Your brother.
感谢你邀请我们
Thank you for inviting us.
伙计们  帮忙安置马匹
Come lad, help with the horses.
-伊格兰王后  -拿水来
- Lady Igraine. - Get the water.
旧地重游定让您回忆起往昔时光吧
Must bring back memories.
很抱歉当初赶你走
I'm sorry for the way that you left.
真的吗
Really?
我希望能弥补当初错误的决定
I had time to requite some of my decisions.
希望您能原谅我
I hope you can forgive me.
彼此彼此
So do I.
大家快请  美味佳肴等着呢
Please. Refreshment awaits!
梅林  很高兴你能来
Merlin. Glad you could come.
重回旧地之邀  我怎会错过
I'd never miss an invite to the old place.
都准备了什么佳肴
Whatcha you cooking?
你肯定不想坐这里吧
This is the last place you wanted to sit.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
几天来  你一直在回避我
You've been avoiding me for days.
我听不到他们在说什么
I can't hear what they're saying.
她的厨房里是不是有人
Does she have someone out back turning water
-能点水成酒啊  -真有意思
- into all this wine? - That's very funny.
天知道我有多久没见过
I haven't seen a spread this good since...
这样的盛况了
God knows.
上帝知道  布拉提斯  他看着呢
Yes, he does, Brastias, and he's watching.
我们齐聚彭德拉根堡
We have all come together here at Castle Pendragon
化干戈为玉帛
to heal old wounds
在国王  亚瑟的领导下
and promote a new future for the land under our king,
共建美好未来
Arthur.
亲爱的弟弟  尊敬的国王
Brother and King, I stand here
作为你的姐姐  你的忠臣
as your sister and loyal subject,
我在此向你表达我对你的爱和忠诚
offering my love and devotion.
敬国王
The king!
你相信她吗
Do you believe her?
我也想啊
I'd love to.
她会令我们如虎添翼
She'd make our endeavour so much stronger.
我无法单枪匹马为这片土地带来和平
I cannot bring peace to this land alone.
我需要盟友  需要家人
I will need my allies and my family.
我向你致敬  摩根
I salute you, Morgan,
我的姐姐  我的盟友
as a sister and an ally.
敬摩根
To Morgan!
她觊觎亚瑟的王位
She covets Arthur's throne.
她声明...   不再争夺王位了
She claims... not anymore.
你相信她吗
You trust her?
现在
And now...
来点娱乐活动吧
...for some entertainment!
-亚瑟  -殿下
- Arthur! - Highness!
你还好吧
Are you all right?
真精彩
Brilliant.
请尽情享受彭德拉根堡的热情款待
Enjoy the hospitality of Castle Pendragon
不要拘泥于形式
in all its forms.
不介意的话  我先失陪了
Don't mind if I do.
高文  还等什么呢
Gawain, what are you waiting for?
去吧
It's fine.
希望您理解  我得拒绝您的好意
You'll understand if I... decline.
-当然  -那让他们都来这吧
- Of course. - Ah, send 'em this way.
不能浪费了这美意
We'll see they don't go to waste.
国王不想找人陪陪吗
Does the king not wish some company?
我有这桌上的人陪我就足够了
I'm very happy with the company around this table.
她们当然不会合所有男人的胃口
They can't feed all of a man's appetites, surely.
你还没有王后
You don't have a queen.
你是个国王  不是个牧师
You're a king, not a priest.
我羡慕你  桂妮维尔
I envy you, Guinevere.
你找到了可以托付真心的男人
You've found a man to whom you can give your whole heart.
我也把心都交给了她
And who has given her his.
我很幸运
I'm very lucky.
发信号
Give the signal.
每座城堡都该有个修女当宠物养着
I think every castle should have a pet nun.
她需要一个家
She needed a home.
于是病患和困苦者的保护人摩根就接纳了她
So Morgan, protector of the sick and needy, took her in.
你美名远扬啊
Your reputation grows.
我吸取了教训
I've learned my lesson.
只为野心而奋斗是没有意义的
Ambition for its own sake is worthless.
你更愿做个贴心的女王
You'd rather be a Queen of Hearts.
卡米洛特已经有一位了
Camelot has one already.
是啊
Indeed.
嘿  醒醒
Hey! Wake up!
管他呢
Aw, to hell with him.
我们不该离开国王
We should not have left the king.
占着茅坑就赶快拉屎
So either shit or get off the pot!
他没事  梅林和里昂提斯跟他在一起呢
He's fine. Merlin and Leontes are with him.
下次再说吧
Maybe some other time.
这么快就要走了么  高文
Leaving the party so soon, Gawain?
你尽情享用吧
You're welcome to her.
好啊  过来吧
Well, come on, then!
着火了
Fire!
怎么了
What was that?
着火了  去弄水来  快
Fire! Get water! Hurry!
快  拿水来
Quick! Get water!
-怎么了  -不知道
- What is it? - I don't know.
去看看
Let's go.
再来点水
More water!
我们需要更多的水
We need more water now!
-火势在蔓延  -去拿水
- The fire's spreading. - Get water!
-去拿水  -去井里打
- Get water! - Water from the well!
-你们所有人  来帮忙  -我们走
- All of you, help! - Let's go.
欧菲尔斯  醒醒  醒醒  欧菲尔斯
Ulfius! Wake up! Come on, Ulfius!
-水  -这是什么  又是娱乐节目吗
- Water! - What is this, more entertainment?
快下来  快下来
Get down! Get down!
亚瑟  她被困住了
Arthur! She's trapped!
把车推过来  把那辆车推过来
Push the cart! Push the cart around!
凯  推啊  推到这边来
Come on, Kay! Push! Around this way!
举
Lift!
拉过来
Pull the cart!
-拉啊  -停下来
- Pull! - Halt!
把我顶上去  把我顶上去
Help lever me up! Help lever me up!
到后面去  后面
Round the back! Round the back!
你  过来帮我
You there! Help me!
数到三  数到三  准备好了吗
On three! On three! Are you ready?
好了
Ready!
一  二  三
One, two, three!
亚瑟
Arthur!
来  来  把车转过来
Come on. Come on. Spin the cart!
-当心  亚瑟  -把车转过来
- Be careful, Arthur! - Turn the cart around!
转到这边
Round this way!
-推啊  推啊  -向前
- Push it up! Push it up now! - Forward!
-接着她  -跳
- Somebody catch her! - Jump!
好了吗
Ready?
起来吧  殿下
Come on, Your Highness.
那真是我见过的最英勇的举动了
That was the bravest thing I've ever seen.
又或是最蠢的
Or the stupidest.
通常是一回事
They're usually one and the same.
你安全了
You're safe.
不论你们有什么防御力量
Whatever defences you have,
让他们马上准备好
get them prepared. Now!
这里  高文  快点  就这样
Here, Gawain! Come on! Yes!
是谁在攻击我们
Who could be attacking us?
是某个知道国王在此的人
Someone knows the king is here.
而且此人还对城堡很了解
Someone who knows this castle well.
应该问是哪一伙敌人
Which enemy could this be?
而不是某一个人
But who?
-可能是奥德伍夫  -谁是奥德伍夫
- It could be Aldwulf. - Who is Aldwulf?
东部的军阀
He's a warrior king from the east,
尤瑟的老对手了
an old enemy of Uther's.
我们交战多次  都是我们赢
We've fought many times. We've always prevailed.
-那他现在来干嘛  -尤瑟已死
- Well, why would he come now? - Uther's dead.
或许他觉得是时候来索取他一直想要的了
Maybe he sees a chance to get something he's always wanted.
-你是说彭德拉根城堡吗  -是领土
- Castle Pendragon? - Territory.
控制权
Control.
要是他能拿下彭德拉根的城堡
If he takes Castle Pendragon, he can move on
就能继而向巴尔东进发
to the Bardon Pass and control
并控制进出山谷的主路
the main route in and out of the valley.
我们所有的补给线
And all our supply routes.
他不放行  我们就无法进行贸易往来
There'd be no trading without his say so.
-卡米洛特就将任他摆布  -他要是在关口
- Camelot would be under his command. - If he held the pass
以重兵把守  我们永远都动不了他
with a large force, we'd never remove him.
我们有人把守关口吗
Do we have anyone defending the pass?
有个叫卢坎的农民是为彭德拉根效忠的
A farmer called Lucan flies the Pendragon colour.
仅此而已吗
And that's it?
要取下巴尔东必须从此经过
In order to take Bardon, you have to come through here.
要是放他们从彭德拉根城堡经过
If they left Castle Pendragon
我们就可以从后面攻击他们
unconquered, their whole rear would be open to assault.
他们是想试试我们的兵力
They want to test our strength.
我们的兵力都留在卡米洛特
Which is in Camelot.
我们的人都不在身边
Our men are not with us.
他大概觉得我不会妨碍他
Maybe he thinks I wouldn't stand in his way.
大家都知道我与先父不合  而且我是女人
Our prior differences are well known, and I'm a woman,
他觉得我不构成威胁
so no threat to his advance.
那他发现我们在这就要大吃一惊了
Well, then he's got a shock coming when he finds us waiting.
-我们人手不够  -亚瑟
- We're only a few. - Arthur,
我的人你随便用  他们都听你的
treat my men as your own. They're yours.
-谢谢  -你有什么人
- Thank you. - What men are they?
忠于尤瑟的人都跟我们去卡米洛特了
Uther's loyal subjects came with us to Camelot.
这些是忠于我的战士
These are warriors loyal to me.
-有多少  -训练精良的四十人卫戍部队
- How many? - A garrison of 40 well-trained men.
天啊  你还真没闲着
My, you have been busy.
从没有人突破彭德拉跟城堡
No one has ever breached Castle Pendragon.
那我们就别开这个先河
Then let's not set a precedent.
不  我们该立刻离开
No, we should leave now,
趁夜色送你回卡米洛特
get you back to Camelot under the cover of darkness.
我才刚刚为联合而举杯  你就让我
I've just sworn a toast to unity, and you want
为了个传言而扔下我姐姐任人宰割吗
to leave my sister vulnerable because of a rumour?
凯是对的  你得活下去
Kay is right. You must survive.
奥德伍夫攻击的  并非你的城堡
It's not your home under Aldwulf attacks.
但这里也是王土
But it is my land.
彭德拉根城堡在我的庇护之下
Castle Pendragon is under my protection.
里昂提斯
Leontes.
你非常了解城堡  你能负责防御吗
You know the castle well. Will you see to the defence?
交给我了
Leave it to me.
找到那些攻击者
Find the attackers,
探明他们的实力  马上回来
assess the weight of their forces, and return.
别和他们交锋
Don't engage them.
不管发生什么  黎明时分必须回来
Whatever happens, be back here by dawn.
-放心吧  -去吧
- You can depend on us. - Go!
有女人又有仗打
A fuck and a fight!
今夜变得如此美妙
This is turning into a good night.
男人对待打仗就像在玩游戏
Men treat all this like some kind of great game.
桂妮维尔  他们是战士
Guinevere, they're warriors.
对于战斗的期待让他们兴奋
The prospect of battle excites them.
怎么  难道我们就坐这里干等吗
What, and we're supposed to just sit here and wait?
外面有野蛮人的军队
Given an army of barbarians out there,
我们还能怎样
what choice do we have?
现在  他们脑中充斥着各种行动和计划
Right now, they are full of planning and action.
但很快  他们会冷静下来进行思考
But soon, they will stop and think.
那时他们便回到我们身边
And that's when they will come to us.
我们会令他们想起自己是为何而战
To remind themselves of why they will fight.
如果我们对他们没信心
And if we doubt them,
他们就会不自信
then they will doubt themselves,
战斗就必将失败
and the battle will be lost.
我们的战士很勇猛
Our champions are stout,
这城堡也固若金汤
and this castle is strong.
所以别害怕
So do not fear.
她们听得全神贯注
They hang on her every word.
你被赐予伊格兰的容貌是有原因的
You were given Igraine for a reason.
找我何事
Did you want something?
我们的人已到位
Our people are in position.
不  不  它们太长了
No, no! They're too long!
这些矛对于近战来说都太长了
These spears are all too long for close-quarter combat.
是吗
Really?
他们会从攻城梯登上城墙
They're coming up siege ladders.
那他们就只能像这样挥动武器
They can only swing their weapons overhand, like so.
一旦他们这样做
The second they do,
你们就得用短矛战斗
you stab with a short spear.
别乱挥  你们要找准位置
And no wild swings. You get right in,
用力向上刺
and you drive it up!
把这些矛都削短一半
Cut half of these down.
让他们在城墙上列队防御
And line them on the walls.
殿下
Highness.
看来你挺喜欢干这些
You look like you're enjoying this.
比起艳舞  我更喜欢打仗
I prefer fighting over dancing.
高文  如果这里干完了
Gawain, if you're done here,
我需要你去东城墙检查一下
I need you to check the men on the east wall.
你现在是在命令我吗  里昂提斯
Are you giving me orders now, Leontes?
你以前防御过这城堡吗
Have you ever defended this castle before?
那就听我的命令吧
Then I'm giving you orders.
里昂提斯
Leontes!
你该待在里面
You should be inside.
我不能就坐着什么都不干
I cannot sit indoors and do nothing.
里昂提斯  让我们帮忙吧
Leontes, let us be helpful.
我们一定可以做些什么
There must be something we can do.
我们需要绷带和药品  去找些来
We need bandages and medicine. Find them.
还有  桂妮维尔...
And Guinevere...
有人告诉过你  你有多美吗
Anyone ever tell you how beautiful you are?
你  每天都在说
You. Every day.
我们需要绷带和药品
We're going to need bandages and medicine.
我带你去拿
Let me show you.
太好了  干得好  兄弟们  继续
Excellent. Well done, men. Keep going.
不  别都放那里
No! Not all there!
将它们散布于城墙上
Spread them out across the wall!
我们需要战士们
We need weapons at hand
随处可以拿到武器
wherever our warriors are positioned.
你还认为我们该来吗
So, you still think we should have come?
你为何如此多虑
Why are you so worried?
这正是你训练的目的  不是吗
This is what you train for, isn't it?
你该感激这次挑战
You should be grateful for the challenge.
我们尚未准备就绪
We're not prepared.
那就好好准备
Then get prepared.
那里应该是谁的防御位置
What men are supposed to be there?
只有你在这儿
So it's just you here,
独自守着城堡
alone in this castle.
我没觉得孤单
I don't feel alone.
你没想过找个丈夫吗
Do you not think about taking a husband?
曾经想过
I've thought about it.
但我能从中得到什么呢
What would I gain from it?
爱情啊  那不是人人都想要的吗
Love. Isn't that what everyone wants?
手握他人之心
Isn't it a burden to
难道不是种负担吗
hold another's heart in your hands?
那是种荣幸
It's a privilege.
如果你伤了他的心呢
What if you damage it?
你不会那样做
Well, you mustn't.
因为那是种信任
That's the trust.
你觉得国王怎么样
How do you feel about the king?
你指哪方面
What do you mean?
他是个贤明的君主吗
Does he make a good ruler?
你丈夫是否像信任我父亲那样  信任他呢
Does your husband believe in him as he did my father?
我想是的  他是个好人
I think so. He's a good man.
也很帅
And handsome!
很帅吗
Is he?
你知道的
You know he is.
可能吧
I suppose.
但我结婚了  不会过于关注
But I'm married, so I don't look.
他会垂青于某位幸运女子
Someone is going to be very lucky.
我肯定他不久便会迎娶一位王后
I'm sure he won't be without a queen for long.
彭德拉根的修女
The Pendragon nun.
希望没打扰你
I've been hoping to bump into you.
你怎么上来了
Should you be up here?
怎么了
Why?
我不该来这里吗
Are there places I shouldn't be?
听说你很了解这古堡
I hear you know this castle of old.
这与建筑无关
It's never the buildings.
建筑里的人所做之事
It's what people do inside them
才是关键
that matters.
一个修女会来这里  真是有趣
Funny place for a woman of faith.
哪里都需要信仰
Faith is needed everywhere.
我想你的女主人将信仰倾注于更加...
I think your mistress puts her faith in more...
...原始的力量了
...primal forces.
她从修道院带回了点...
She came back from the nunnery with some...
并非基督徒的
interesting talents
有趣的才能
not particularly Christian.
现在你又出现在这里
And now here you are.
你发誓永不泄密了吗
Did you take a vow of silence?
我需要避难之所
I needed sanctuary,
于是摩根提供给了我
and Morgan gave it.
那她能得到何种回报
And what she get in return?
有人过来了
There's someone coming.
看起来他好像受伤了
It looks like he's wounded.
打开城门
Open the gates!
帮我扶他下马
Help me get him down!
欧菲尔斯  快点
Ulfius! Come on.
带他进屋
Get him inside.
带他进屋  快走
Get him inside! Move!
回到各自岗位
Back to your posts!
是谁
Who is it?
是侦察兵
It's the scout.
出什么事了
What happened?
一群士兵正在做进攻准备
A host of men making preparation for an attack.
谁的
Whose?
-谁的兵  -奥德伍夫
- Whose men? - Aldwulf's.
在哪
Where?
正向东袭来  即刻便到
To the east. They will come soon.
有多少人
How many?
足以踏平这里
The castle will be crushed.
我们已做好准备
We're prepared.
不必惊慌
Nothing's changed.
你做得很好
You did well.
-开门  -跟上
- Open! - Come on!
-不  等等  -这是干什么
- No!! Wait!! - What are they doing?!
谁让他们出城的
Who gave the order for them to ride out?!
是我
I did.
如果我们能攻其不备
If we can attack them before their plans are complete,
我的人便能奇袭得手
my men will have the element of surprise.
这样的蠢事你也做得出来
That was the stupidest thing you could have done!
我们还不知他们的战术
We have no idea what those plans are.
-简直是自寻死路  -高文  够了
- It's tactical suicide! - Gawain, enough!
是我考虑不周  亚瑟
I'm sorry, Arthur.
现在开始从长计议
So now we take a different strategy.
我们要同心协力
Plan and work together.
-大家速速归位  -进去
- Back to your posts, men. - Back inside.
关城门
Seal the gates.
现在我们还有二十多个人手
So we have about 20, 25 able-bodied men.
-这点人不够守卫整个城墙  -知道了
- That's not enough to defend the entire perimeter. - OK.
假设他迎头攻上  我们要集中火力
Well, say he comes at us head-on. We concentrate our forces
守住城门  制造人手众多的假象
at the gate, making them seem more than they are.
如果他从后方进攻呢
And if he attacks from the rear?
那我们便从前方折到后方
Then we make a run for it from the front.
梅林  还有什么要补充吗
Merlin, anything to add?
那好  行动吧
Right. Let's get to it.
我这儿还有一计
There's another tactic.
我的人可暂时拖住他们
My attack would provide a diversion
你们可以乘机回城
and you could make it home.
那你这里岂不成了空城一座
Leaving you totally defenceless.
我若逃了  一切努力都将前功尽弃
If I ran, everything we're working for would be over.
没到身首异处的境地就不会前功尽弃
It's over if your head's stuck on a pike.
你或许该接受摩根的好意
Maybe you should take Morgan up on her kind offer.
既然还有二十五人可用  那就全力应战
If 25 men is all we have, then we'll have to make do with that.
还有我们
You have us.
我们也能打仗
We can fight.
不  不  不行
No. No, that's not gonna happen.
可你们一旦失利
And if you fall?
我们岂有善终
What of our fate?
战场可不是女人该去的地方
The battlement is no place for women.
我可不想守在屋里等着被蹂躏
I am not hiding indoors awaiting to be raped.
我宁愿手持长剑死战死沙场
I'd rather die with a sword in my hand.
她说得对
She's right.
大家都是一条船上的人
We're all in this together.
-陛下  -让她们自己决定命运
- Your Majesty-- - Let them decide their own fate.
如果她们会射箭掷矛  还是能帮上忙的
And if they can pull a bow or throw a spear, then we need them.
关键是瞄准
It's all about the position.
要稳住
You need to keep it stiff.
向后拉  把握好发射时机
Pull back, and know when it's time to release.
他就没个正经时候
Does he take nothing seriously?
笑着死哭着死都一样
I can die laughing, or I can die crying.
反正我是死定了
The only certain thing is I'm going to die.
梅林质疑我了
Merlin was asking about me.
他怀疑我和你的巫术有关联
He suspects me of having a hand in your powers.
他很聪明
He's clever.
可亚瑟相信我是真心对他好
But Arthur wants to believe in my love.
我本来想着  "去赴个宴
Here was me thinking, "Go to a feast!
跳跳舞  再邂逅一个
"Have a dance, meet a man--
风度翩翩的美男"  结果呢
a decent one with manners". Now look at me.
现在自己却小命难保
I've even got to save myself from a fate worse than death.
我会保护你
I'll look after you.
放低弓箭时  将手臂伸直
Keep your left arm straight as you lower the arrow...
-好箭法  -这可不是猎兔子
- She's good. - We're not hunting rabbits.
当然  猎的是人
No, men.
靶子更大  跑得更慢
And they're bigger, and slower.
这些小把戏有什么用
What use is all this?
奥德伍夫大军一来  都无济于事
When Aldwulf arrives with his forces, it's over.
也许  静观其效吧
Maybe. We'll wait and see.
如果能让他们在这里待到明早
If we can keep them all inside till morning,
那些人便不会再怀疑我有二心
the others will be certain of my loyalty.
-那梅林呢  -也没事
- And Merlin? - Won't matter.
他会以为就算我有野心
He'll think we pose no military threat,
没有兵力也不成气候
whatever my ambitions.
男人啊
Men.
再聪明的人也无法否认兵力决定一切
Even the clever ones think that armies decide everything.
希望如此
Let's hope so.
等待可不是战术
Waiting is no strategy for war.
-你不一起吗  -不
- You're not joining in? - Hm! No.
我知道自己不会有任何帮助
I know I'd make no difference.
但如果这样能让他们忘记将要面临的血战
But if it keeps their minds off what...
也未尝不是好事
...might come, then good.
我相信亚瑟和他的护卫们
I'll put my faith in Arthur and his champions.
你觉得...
Do you think...
一个人能够改变本性
...it's possible to rise above your beginnings?
变得更好吗
To be better than your blood?
摩根  你是真的改过了么
Have you really changed, Morgan?
你比谁都清楚  过去无法改变
You know better than anyone that we can't change the past,
只能弥补
only atone for it.
我会向大家证明自己
I will prove myself to you all.
我保证
I promise.
-我做得怎样  -很好
- How did I do? - You did well.
这是我忠诚的印记
A mark of my devotion.
仅以此表示我的谢意
A symbol of my gratitude.
你要走
Are you leaving?
我要去找奥德伍夫
I'm going to go and find Aldwulf.
亲手杀了他
And kill him myself.
这是我听过最蠢的事了
That's the stupidest thing I have ever heard.
你想就这样坐等奥德伍夫攻破城门么
You'd rather wait until Aldwulf is upon the gates?
国王已经下令  我们有责任服从
The king has given us his orders. It's our duty to follow.
你倒是责任重大
You and your duty--
要服从国王
to the king,
要善待妻子
to your wife,
还要敬奉上帝
to God.
你哪来的那么多时间啊
How do you find time in the day?
-你这是嫉妒  -嫉妒你
- You sound jealous. - Of you?
你为何执意要出去
Why are you so keen to go out there?
这无异于自投罗网
It's a suicide mission.
自投罗网
Suicide?
等待才是自投罗网
Waiting is suicide.
我宁愿战死也不愿等待
And I'd rather fight than wait.
即便要死
If I'm going to die,
我也要自己选择死法
it'll be on my own terms.
你哪儿都不能去  这是命令
You're not going anywhere. That's an order.
别动不动拿命令压我
I've told you about giving me orders.
-让我走  -我不会放你走的
- Now leave me be. - I'll not let you go.
你阻止不了我
You couldn't stop me.
为何你总是要唱反调
Why does everything with you have to be a confrontation?
国王需要你留在这里
The king needs you here.
你话太多了  里昂提斯
You talk too much, Leontes.
一如你的经文
Like your Scriptures--
字太多
too many words.
回去
Go back inside.
你知道你赢不了我
You know you can't beat me.
我不需要赢你
I don't have to.
你说自己不需要别人  并非如此吧
You say you need no one. That's not true, is it?
-闭嘴  -事实是
- Shut up. - The truth is...
你不会和人相处
you can't handle your own company.
你不了解我
You don't know me.
我了解你
I do,
因为在你身上  我看见了自己的影子
because when I look at you, I see myself!
这是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?!
我发现他想离开
I found him trying to leave!
是真的吗
Is this true?
回答我
Answer your king!
我想自己去攻打奥德伍夫
I wanted to face Aldwulf myself.
你训练我们
You trained us.
我听取了你的训导  现在你得听我的
I listened to you. Now you listen to me.
你不能一人孤身杀敌
You're not fighting on your own.
我们在这里集结
We are banded together here.
团结成一个整体  没人例外
We stand as one. No exceptions.
没人例外
No exceptions.
现在各就各位  保持警惕
Now man the battlements, and keep watch.
走吧  护卫
Come along, champion.
你相信她吗
Do you believe her?
你明显怀疑
You obviously doubt.
你自诩学富五车  料事如神
I know you're the self-appointed font of all knowledge,
却没料到这个  是吧
but you didn't see this coming, did you?
我们不知道这是什么
We don't know what this is.
暂时还不知道
Not yet.
你怀疑奥德伍夫真在外面吗
So you doubt that Aldwulf is out there?
我怀疑一切
I doubt everything.
是啊  还怀疑每个人
Hm! Yes, and everyone.
为什么
Why?
想知道我在想什么吗
You want to get inside my head? Hmm?
想见我所见吗
See what I see? Hmm?
是的
Yes.
你以为知识就是力量
You think knowledge is power.
知识其实是痛苦
Knowledge is pain.
你想要吗
Do you want this?
让我们共同分担
Share your burden.
摩根杀了尤瑟
Morgan killed Uther.
用的毒
Poisoned him.
他拒绝了她
He rejected her,
所以她就杀了他
and she killed him.
帮帮我们
Help us!
那不是真的
That can't be true.
你的表情说明你知道那是真的
The look on your face tells me you know it is.
你瞒着我
You kept this from me?
你还瞒着什么事
What else are you holding back?
很多事
Plenty.
但你不能告诉亚瑟
But you can't tell Arthur.
他身处险境
He's in danger.
若摩根想杀他
If Morgan wanted to kill him,
她现在已经得手了
she would have done it by now.
我们是他的力量和保护伞
We are his strength and protection.
他得知这事不会有好处的
No good will come of his knowing.
上帝
Father God,
今晚请派您的天使与我们一起
send your angels to be with us this night.
掩护我们的...
Cover our--
抱歉打扰了
I'm sorry.
你想一个人呆着吗
Did you want to be alone?
今晚没人会想独处  不是吗
That's the last thing any of us want tonight, isn't it?
-信仰能抚慰你吗  -是的
- Your faith comforts you?  - It does.
当我们在这样的夜晚  被疑惑缠身
A good thing on a night like this,
信仰是不错的选择
when doubts assail us.
上帝给我了我所愿的一切
God has given me all I could want.
他也可以轻易收回
He could take it from me just as easily.
他为何要收回  你是如此虔诚
Why would he? You are so devoted.
如果那虔诚受到了考验呢
What if that devotion were tested?
如果明天我就要失去朋友和爱人呢
If tomorrow saw me losing friends and loved ones?
那不是虔诚信仰的定义吗
Is that not the definition of true faith?
你害怕会失去什么吗
You fear that something will be taken from you?
我半夜醒来  感觉冰冷
I wake at night, cold,
害怕会失去桂妮维尔
fearing that Guinevere will be taken from me.
这是对我罪孽的惩罚
Retribution for my sins.
我担忧的不是你对上帝的信仰
It's not your faith in God I'd worry about,
而是你错信他人
but your faith in man.
听着  你有护卫
Listen to me. You have champions--
凯  里昂提斯
Kay, Leontes.
你无须孤军奋战
You do not have to do this alone.
我不能躲在他们身后
I cannot hide behind them.
让他们照顾你并非躲避
It isn't hiding to let them care for you.
而是爱护
To love you.
我花了很长时间才找到你
It's taken me so long to find you,
我现在不能失去你
I can't bear the thought of losing you now.
你无需证明你对我的爱
You do not need to prove your love to me.
我知道的
I know it.
我也爱你
And I return it.
你不仅是我母亲  更是卡米洛特的母亲
You're not just a mother to me, but to all of Camelot.
亚瑟  你要去哪里
Arthur, where are you going?
今晚要把一切说清楚
Tonight is not a night to leave things unsaid.
知道吗  我刚才真想杀了你
You know I wanted to kill you back there?
我发现了
I noticed.
你身手不错
You fought well.
我无法打败你
I couldn't beat you.
这是好事  真的
It's a good thing, really.
我以前战无不胜
I always could before.
这是信仰给你的力量吗
Is that what faith gives you?
我长年浴血奋战
I spent years bathed in blood.
男人之战  感觉是种荣誉
Man versus man. It felt like it had honour.
直到有一天的战事中
Then one day we rode into battle.
我们黎明时分进入一个村庄  战事激烈
We entered a village at dawn; the fighting was fierce,
我对付一个战士
and I took arms against a warrior.
正当我把他击倒在地时
Just as I flung him to the ground,
另一个人跳上了我的背
another jumped on my back. I...
我毫不犹豫把他扔在地上
I didn't even think. I just threw him to the floor
一剑刺中了他
and I drove my sword through him.
但这战士不是成人  只是个小孩
Except the warrior wasn't a man; it was a boy,
不足12岁
no more than 12.
他甚至还拿不起剑
He could barely lift the sword that he held.
我看见他母亲对儿子之死伤心欲绝
And I watched his mother, all that pain and grief for her son.
那晚还是如常举行庆功宴
That night we feasted to our victory as usual,
但我毫无感觉
and I felt nothing.
那天午夜后  我
Later on in the middle of the night I...
我祈祷了
I prayed.
我祈求上帝原谅我
I asked God to forgive me.
他原谅你了吗
Did he?
-能跟你聊聊吗  -你不该来这里
- Can I speak to you? - You shouldn't be in here.
我要说的话不能被外人知晓
What I need to say cannot be said in public.
那你就该绝口不提
Then you shouldn't be saying it to me at all.
我们之间的...
How it was...
感觉  我以前从没意识到
...between us. I've never known that before.
从没有过那样的感觉
Never felt like that.
够了
Stop.
请让我说完
Please!
我对明日之战没有把握
I don't know if we can prevail tomorrow.
亚瑟
Arthur.
明天也许会成为我们生命的终结点
Tomorrow could be the end of all of us,
我不想带着满腹心事死去
and I don't want to die without having said this.
里昂提斯是我的护卫
Leontes is my champion.
我尊敬他  我永远不会
I honour him, and would never do anything
做出破坏你们婚姻的事
to break your marriage.
但我要你知道
But I need you to know...
我爱你
...I love you.
你走吧
Go.
求你
Please.
奥德伍夫  你个狗杂种
Ardulf, you bog-dwelling inbred!
等你跟你姐姐交媾完
When you're finished interfering with your sister,
来挑战彭德拉根的男人们试试吧
come and have a go at the men of Pendragon!
-懦夫  -很久以前
- Cowards!  - Long long ago in this...
-奥德伍夫  -在这古老的土地上
- Ardulf!  - ...ancient land
两山之间  战事突发
A battle took place where 2 hills now stand
尸横遍野
And on the plain
血流成河
There lay the slain
生灵涂炭  胜者尤败
For neither the battle was won
里昂提斯爱桂妮维尔胜过爱生命
Leontes loves Guinevere more than life itself.
她是他的全部未来
She is the future he pins all his hopes upon.
卡米洛特的希望则寄托在了亚瑟身上
And Camelot's hopes rest on Arthur's honour.
亚瑟和他护卫间的隔阂
A wedge between Arthur and his champion
能毁掉一切
could bring it all down.
他们都对伊格兰夫人信任有加
And they all confide in the Lady Igraine.
万事已备
I have what I need.
你确定你想这么做吗
Are you sure this is what you want?
你说过我被赐予这能力是有原因的
You said I'd been given the gift for a reason.
现在我知道原因何在了
Now I know what it is.
-骑士  -有骑士过来了
- Riders! - Riders approaching!
他们回来了
The men return!
发生了何事
What happened?
其他人呢
Where are the others?
死了
Dead.
只剩了我们几个
We are all that remain.
我说了这是胡来
I told you this was madness!
敌军情况如何  离你们还有多远
And what of the enemy, how far behind you?
他们走了
They are gone.
-去哪了  巴尔东吗  -听他说完
- Gone where? To Bardon Pass? - Let him speak.
他们走了  我们战胜了他们
They're gone. We defeated them.
什么
You did what?
我们突袭了他们
We took them by surprise.
战斗很惨烈
The fighting was vicious.
其他战士们呢
Where are the rest of your comrades?
在战斗中牺牲了
Fallen on the battlefield.
全部吗
All of them?
奥德伍夫死了吗  可否见到他的尸体
Is Aldwulf dead? Did you claim his body?
有几个人逃走了
The last few fled.
我们无力再追了
We had no men left to follow.
你们做得很好
You have done well.
你们做出了巨大的牺牲
The sacrifice you have made is huge.
我的人以为彭德拉根而战为豪
My men are proud to fight under the Pendragon banner.
姐姐
Sister.
我们都欠你的情
We are in your debt.
但你的人元气大伤  希望你能
But with your men so weakened, maybe you should accompany us
跟我们一起回卡米洛特
back to Camelot.
我们还要为勇士们准备葬礼
We have brave men to bury.
我的根在这里
My place is here.
-太可笑了  -你是说你很遗憾
- What a tease. - So what you're saying is
我们没去参加那必死无疑的战斗
you're disappointed we didn't face certain death?
我是说  我很遗憾自己完全错过了那战斗
What I'm saying is, I'm sad I missed the fight completely.
摩根的人取得了一场辉煌的胜利
Morgan's men have claimed a famous victory.
她的传奇有又新料了
Her legend grows.
你怀疑她
You doubt her?
没有他不怀疑的人  他就这样
He doubts everyone. It's his way.
总是一副高深莫测的样子
Keep up the whole inscrutable man of magic thing.
我只是觉得死要见尸
I just want to see the dead bodies.
我们熬过了这个夜晚  我很欣慰
I'm relieved we all made it out of this night.
是的
Yes.
他们都等着呢  不如...
Uh, they're all waiting, so...
你究竟有何魔力
What is it about you?
你这张脸为何能让男人们甘愿沉沦
What is it about that face that makes men weak?
准备好了吗
Are we ready?
好了  我只是...
Yes. I just wanted...
想再看这地方最后一眼
...one last look at the place.
你怀念这里
You miss it?
不
No.
我已经有新家了
I've got a new home now.
卡米洛特
Camelot.
有何指示
What are the orders?
去召集一些人
You are to recruit some men--
不是我们的人
not ours--
要找其他对亚瑟心怀不满的人
others disaffected with Arthur.
去袭击巴尔东的边区村落
You will attack the outpost at Bardon Pass.
这能把国王引过去
This will draw out the king.
别给他留机会
Offer him no quarter.
我要摩根亲自对我下令
I want to hear that from Morgan herself.
我已经把命令传达给你了
You're hearing it from me.
需要我告诉她你拒绝了吗
Or shall I tell her that you refuse?
我会做的
I'll do it.
你没事吧
Are you all right?
没事  只是有点累
Fine. Just weary.
昨晚是个漫长之夜
It was a long night.
修女
Oh, Sister.
我知道这都是摩根的命令
I know that this is Morgan's bidding.
放我走  我保证你不会受到责罚
Let me go and I will make sure that you are not punished.
你真以为
Do you really think
国王不会在意我去了哪吗
that the king will not wonder where I am?
他不会发现的
I know he won't.
回家真好
It's good to be home.
是啊
Yes.
真好
It is.